PRADEEP KUMAR SENIOR TEAM LEADER - TECHNOLOGY

New Delhi, India • +91 -9711595609 • pradeepbhardwaj.it@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/pradeep-kumar-9ba58535/

SUMMARY

Senior Team Leader with expertise spanning a range of programming languages and tools, including PHP with a focus on the Laravel Framework, Python, and MySQL, which enables me to develop robust web applications and manage databases effectively. Ventured into NoSQL databases, having worked with MongoDB, which adds versatility to my data management capabilities. Familiar with front-end technologies like JQuery with a valuable experience in cloud computing using AWS thereby hosting and managing applications in the cloud.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Consultant (Technology)

Jan 2024 - Till Date Log9 Materials Bengaluru, India

Products - https://photonboxx.com/

Senior Team Leader (Technology)

Dec 2020 – Dec 2023 Mosaic Digital (Hindustan Times Group Company) New Delhi, India

Products - VCCEdge (B2B, Fintech)- vccedge.com/index.php | VCCircle (B2C, Media)- www.vccircle.com, SalesEdge (B2B, Sales) - https://www.salesedge.tech/

• Responsible for project management, team supervision, collaboration between the internal teams and technical suppervision.

Team Leader (Technology)

Oct 2017 - Nov 2020 Mosaic Digital (NewsCorp Group Company) New Delhi, India

Products - VCCEdge (B2B, Fintech)- vccedge.com/index.php | VCCircle (B2C, Media)- www.vccircle.com, SalesEdge (B2B, Sales) - https://www.salesedge.tech/

Responsible for planning and development of the products

Senior Developer (Technology)

Feb 2011 – Oct 2017 Mosaic Media Ventures Pvt. Ltd. (Startup) New Delhi, India Products - VCCEdge (B2B, Fintech)- vccedge.com/index.php | VCCircle (B2C, Media)- www.vccircle.com

Created all these products from scratch.

EDUCATION

MCA - Full Time 2007 - 2010

B S Anangpuria Institute of Technology and Management, Faridabad, Haryana

B.Sc. - Full Time 2004 - 2007 University College Rohtak, **Haryana**

CERTIFICATIONS

Udemy

The Complete Python Developer Certification Course

Udemy

Modern React with Redux

SKILLS

- Cross-Functional Team Leadership
- Stakeholder Management and Collaboration
- Agile Methodology and Product Development
- Backlog Management and Prioritization
- Ability to Manage Multiple Priorities and Deadlines
- Analytical and Problem-Solving Skills
- User Experience Design and Optimization
- Communication and Presentation Skills

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- PHP (Laravel Framework)
- PYTHON
- MYSql
- AWS
- MongoDB
- JQuery
- GIT